

Guilherme Emilio Guain Peixinho Front-end Developer

- ⊠ guilherme.guain@gmail.com
- **(**11) 9 7609-8780

- m guilhermeguain.com.br
- São Paulo, SP Brazil

I have been working with web development since 2012, when I started in a communication agency creating websites in Wordpress. After 8 years of experience in this technology, I started a specialization in React.js. In addition, I also follow Clean Code and SOLID principles, respecting technical SEO practices with a focus on problem solving.

HARD SKILLS HTML/CSS JAVASCRIPT/REACT.JS **TYPESCRIPT TECHNICAL SEO DESIGN/LAYOUT** GIT



TECHS & TOOLS

PRIMARY: React.js, TypeScript, Next.js, ESLint, Git, Tailwind CSS and Postman.

SECONDARY: PHP, Node.js, MySQL, WordPress, AMP, GraphQL, Sass and Gulp.

DESIGN: Figma, Photoshop e Illustrator.

LANGUAGES

PORTUGUESE: Native ENGLISH: Intermediate

Experience

Health Protection

Front-end Developer 09/2020 - 10/2022









The project was developed using Next.js with TypeScript and tools such as the Context API, Axios, Tailwind CSS, Chakra UI, ESLint, and React Query. For content management, we used Sanity CMS. My activities involved front-end development, API integration, component and page creation, maintenance and bug fixing, and also continuous deployment with Netlify and Vercel.

Toxicologia Pardini

Full-stack Developer 08/2018 - present











Reference company in toxicology testing where I act as a full-stack developer responsible for the development and maintenance of the site. Among the main activities are: on-page SEO optimization, implementation of new features, bug fixes and integrations with internal systems, CRM and ERP.

360 Comunicação Digital WordPress Developer 05/2013 - 08/2018







As a communication agency focused on positioning companies with digital marketing, I participated in the whole process, from the layout creation to the publication of the site in Wordpress. My activities involved structuring and customizing WordPress themes and plugins, performance optimization and SEO, landing page creation and API integration.

Education

React.js - Ignite ROCKETSEAT	HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Bootstrap ALURA	11/2017 - 02/2018 Online
GoStack - Node.js, React.js and React Native ROCKETSEAT	Programming logic and PHP	10/2012 - 06/2014 São Paulo, SP
Nanodegree Front-end Web Developer	Graphic Design Technician ALPHA CHANNEL	05/2012 - 05/2013 São Paulo, SP